[rain pattering]
[thunder rumbling]
[dog whimpers]
[opera music playing in the
background]
[bird squawks]
-[thunder booms]
-[bird squawks]
[opera music continues]
[bird squawking]
[dog whimpering]
[thunder rumbling]
[bird squawks]
[thunder booms]
[opera music continues]
[thunder rumbles]
[knocking]
[Marcos] Come in.
[door opens]
[Kostas] I'm sorry, sir.
Something has happened.
It's about your son.
[radio chattering in foreign
language]
[rain pattering]
[radio chattering in foreign
language]
[footsteps approaching]
[Kostas] Sir.
We found him.
Marcos, I'm so sorry.
[lighter flicks]
[somber music]
[Marcos] Just leave me alone.
[somber music intensifies]
[wind blowing]
[birds chirping]
[waves lapping]
[men chattering]
[Marcos] Sofia,
my little girl.
I am here at our house,
writing my thoughts
just before everyone arrives
for your party.
I've missed you so much.
I want you to know that I don't
like what I have to do,
but I have to do it.
[chattering]
I'm sure you'll understand,
that you'll agree
with me in the end.
We'll do what needs to be done,
and we'll carry on.
That's what a family does best.
That's what makes us special.
Can't wait to put my arms
around you.
[gentle music playing]
[curtains open]
[footsteps approaching]
[gentle music continues,
singing in foreign language]
[telephone rings]
[Marcos speaking
foreign language]
[telephone clicks]
[tape recorder starts]
[Marcos] I said I wasn't
available for anyone today.
[man on phone] Yes, sir.
But it's really important.
[Marcos] Just tell me
where they are.
-29 North, 33 East.
-[water faucet running]
They're already right there.
No, no.
Tell Stavros there's
no turning back.
That's just rumors.
Listen, we [chuckles] we are
the fucking pirates.
Just write down what I say.
Stavros crossed today
or never come back.
I know the pass is clean.
Don't listen to anyone, Marcos.
Send me a telex
with his position,
after they have crossed.
-[gentle music continues]
-[tape recorder stops]
[dog whimpers, barks]
Good morning my boy.
The bath is ready sir.
Thank you, Marisa.
[Marcos speaking
foreign language]
[footsteps receding]
[Marcos] Run down to her.
Take Icarus with you.
[dog panting]
[radio static, chattering]
-It's an honor.
-Welcome sir.
-Very nice to see you again.
-Nice to see you too.
-Carlos. I don't believe it.
-Hi.
[indistinct chattering]
Thank you, Jack.
[upbeat music playing]
[boat engine revving]
Master's orders, no commercial
allowed on the island.
Your daughter looks beautiful.
Hello, Kostas.
[indistinct chatter]
[party guests] Woo, woo!
[speedboat roars]
[Marisa] Sofia!
Sofia.
[radio static]
[dramatic music]
[birds chirping]
I'm so sorry, sir.
I... It's because of the baby.
We don't sleep well at night.
-Yanis, right?
-Yeah.
Yes, sir.
She's Yanis.
She's a month-old today,
Mr. Marcos.
It's okay.
I know it's hard at first,
but tuck in your shirt
and get your shit together.
Thank you, sir.
It won't happen again.
[Marcos] Of course it won't.
[door opens, closes]
Impressive, Marcos.
Congratulations.
It's an exact copy of a room
at Mount Sinai.
Even a little better, maybe.
Is there something I don't
know, dear?
No, I'm fine, don't worry.
It's just
that I don't want to entrust
everything to a damn Greek army
helicopter, that's all.
I feel safer with all this here.
And I also still
have my flare gun.
[laughing]
Come on.
I'd feel much better if I put
some of this equipment on you.
You're the only man I ever let
unbutton my shirt.
Don't tell Sofia
about any of this.
I don't want her to worry
for no reason.
As you wish.
I saw her a moment ago
on the pier.
She looked beautiful
and wild like her father.
Sofia, 25 already, unbelievable.
It's not easy being your
daughter, you know.
Okay, let's see.
Breathe.
[inhaling]
And let the air out slowly.
[exhaling]
Okay.
Daniel would be 28 now.
[somber music]
He'd be boss
of 10,000 employees,
and I'd be able
to start resting.
Finally.
I'm fine, Patrick.
Really, my friend.
Thank you for coming.
I don't like the sound of your
right clunk.
But at the end of the day,
if you don't destroy yourself,
no one will.
[Marisa] How have you been?
You've been gone
for too many years.
How have you been?
[Sofia] Come on! [chuckling]
Just been gone for four years.
Well, I missed you.
I missed you, too.
How are you?
Like, how is it all going here?
Well, you know.
I mean, the first few days,
it's like a paradise.
But any longer
than that, it feels like a cage.
So...
Yeah.
But I'm good.
Better than ever, maybe.
[man] Marisa!
[Marisa] Fuck.
I have to go
or my father will kill me.
Or my father would kill you.
Oh, yeah, well, I'd rather
have my father kill me.
Anyway, listen, why don't you
take me with you when you leave?
Yeah, you wanna come?
See you.
[recording tape plays]
[Sofia on recording] Hi.
No, I'm in London.
Yes.
[chuckling] It's a safe line.
Yeah.
And you'll have to accept it.
[recorder rewinding]
[chuckling] It's a safe line.
Yeah.
And you'll have to accept it.
I'm gonna go all the way
with this baby.
[recorder rewinding]
Go all the way with this baby.
My time has come.
[record plays upbeat music]
[water splashing]
[guests chattering]
[woman singing in foreign
language]
Now Patrick, you're going to
have to excuse me.
Okay, Marcos.
Great Timoleon, my friend.
[laughing]
How are yo so, long time.
I'm so sorry my wife
couldn't come.
She stayed in the palace taking
care of her father.
Anyway, I'm going to
introduce you, Olga,
my personal assistant.
It's a great pleasure
to meet you.
How is General Franco?
[clicks tongue]
Where is your daughter, Sofia?
You tell me.
[all laughing]
Still working, Mr. Forster.
Patrikios.
-Good to see you.
-Good to see you too.
[Forster] Yeah, this was
just a few days ago.
I wonder if the marquis came
for more than just the party.
You are the expert here.
Who is this Englishman
over there?
[indistinct chatter]
He's nobody.
There he is.
-Our Champion, my boy, Carlos.
-Marcos.
-How are you?
[speaking foreign language]
[Marcos laughing] Bravo.
My friends, excuse me, I must
go greet my wife.
I'm looking forward
to meeting her.
I'm such a fan of the signora.
Of course, Olga, of course.
Right now, I'll tell her to come
over and say hello.
Thank you.
Forster, come with me
to my office.
[background music
continues playing]
Well, we should've
seen that coming.
We all know what
Marcos is like.
The wealthy bourgeoisie is our
irreconcilable enemy.
His wealth is founded
on our poverty.
Stalin.
A declared enemy is always
much easier to fight.
You know, they've already made
a movie about me, Forster.
You mean "The Godfather?"
No, it's about a big shark.
Surprised to see the fascist
marquis here.
Have a seat.
Never judge a man who makes
business with another man.
Aren't you doing business
with me?
By the way, I haven't read it.
I've been working on this for
two years.
It's your life
we're talking about.
Aren't you interested?
Yeah, I really don't understand.
I mean, I thought you called me
here to give me an answer.
Why am I here?
[coin flips]
Julius Caesar was the first
Roman emperor to mint coins
with his face on them.
He wanted to forge his legend.
He wanted to be talked about
from South Germania to Africa.
Why do you think
that was, Forster?
Because it was good
for business.
In any case, the first emperor
was Octavian, sir.
Caesar was a dictator.
Oh.
You're very well educated.
But the things that are most
important are those learned
only through experience.
Why the fuck do you
think I invited you
to my daughter's party?
[door opens]
-Papa!
-Oh!
-[Marcos] Darling. [laughing]
-[Sofia] I missed you.
Hello.
When did the two
of you last meet?
Uh, New York.
[Sofia] Or London.
Yeah, I-I think.
[Sofia] So that's what you two
have been cooking up.
Is it pure fiction
or is it based on true events,
Mr. Forster?
[Marcos] Sofia.
-Yeah?
-Please, put on some clothes
and go downstairs and say hello.
But the party's
not until tonight.
[Marcos] I know.
[Sofia chuckles]
I'll leave you to it then.
See you at the party.
[door closes]
I'll talk about it later,
Forster.
-See you later!
-Hey, we're gonna go change.
[man on microphone] Check,
check, one, two, one, one.
Appetite, my friend, appetite.
It is the main source
of phosphorus
and phosphato in the world.
Necessary for the production of
fertilizantes minerales,
which is the future
of farming in the whole world.
Good, the 85% of the appetite is
in our part of Sahara.
The part, just the part Henry
wants us to leave.
[Marcos] My friend.
Oh, thanks.
Ah, good.
Um, you can keep the ports,
all of them,
from Laayoune to Dakhla.
We go out without one bullet.
We leave everything for Morocco.
And then you and I and Henry,
we get the fucking
apartheid mines.
I know what it's like to sell
something that you
don't really have.
Come on.
Please.
Just let's go for it.
Look, Franco is almost dead,
it's going to be over very soon.
No trial, no deal with the past.
We'll leave the Sahara and I
promise I prepare everything
for Henry to put us
in fucking NATO.
All the airports too.
Okay, take them,
take the airports.
[chuckles] I know you
want my son.
Good, take him too.
My boy's clean, fucking clean.
I see you brought all your
merchandising here, interesting.
But still, my little girl can be
tougher to convince than
a New York Banker.
[birds chirping]
-[wind blowing]
-[birds squawking]
[Olivia] That's it.
I won't wait around
for his permission.
I'm going now.
[Patrick] Honey, wait,
don't confront him.
It's the world today.
By the way,
who's this Jack coming with you?
I can't say I like him.
I can understand that, but you
know, he's one of
the best lawyers in New York.
-Oh.
-Mm-hmm.
Yeah, we've already
reached that point.
Oh, Marcos hasn't told me
anything,
but I'm not really surprised.
After you, my dear, there won't
be anyone to put up with him.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Ma'am, Mr. Marcos
wants to see you.
Mmm, at last.
-Not now.
-What?
This is the reason why I'm here.
I'll tell you about it later.
Thank you, Jack.
Marisa, you look so beautiful.
[slow romantic music]
I bought you this one,
when we met in Madrid.
Remember?
Hm.
Tell me something, is this part
of your plan to humiliate me
even further?
[Marcos] It's all right.
I'm going to accept your terms.
That Jack of yours knows how to
put zeros on a piece of
paper, that's for sure.
You shouldn't have come
with him.
You won't be needing him.
Just like that?
Are you all right?
Yes, honey.
Don't worry.
I'm fine.
I feel like I'm at the
beginning of something.
We're going to be divorcees.
Like in the movies.
American movie-style divorcees.
I'll always be your best
friend in the world.
[both laughing]
Your generosity
always scared me more
than your temper ever did.
Your father once told me that
a marriage based on love is
like a sandcastle.
Well, let's make our divorce
like a nice beach where we
can get together every
once in a while.
[Olivia] Mm-mm.
Just one thing, darling, I'm
asking you to help me with
Sofia tonight.
I need you.
[Olivia sighing]
Don't you remember your
daughter doesn't really like me?
It never had anything
to do with you.
It's her way of punishing me.
I know deep down she knows how
much you love her.
I'm serious, Olivia, I'm going
to sign your papers,
and you're gonna help
me with this.
-[water lapping]
-[birds squawking]
[Sofia] You made it,
Mr. Forster.
Are you gonna get in?
I'm afraid I don't swim with
sharks around.
Will you help me out?
[Sofia giggling]
I wonder what your father's
gonna say about that.
[Sofia laughing]
He's not gonna
like it at first.
That's for sure.
But when he realizes,
when he really understands that
he's gonna be a grandfather.
Papa's getting softer.
He's getting softer in age.
No, he's getting older,
that's for sure.
Softer, I don't know.
[laughing] He is.
I'm going to do it.
It's my time.
And I'm finding my place
and you have a place with me.
If you're not a chicken.
Are you a coward?
[Sofia] Come here, baby.
It all begins and ends here.
[Sofia] Hm.
[sensual music]
[both moaning]
I hope someone is watching.
Come inside me.
[moaning]
-[both moaning]
-[sensual music continues]
[camera shutter clicking]
[water bubbling]
[recording tape plays]
[Marcos] I'm serious, Olivia.
I'm going to sign your papers.
And you're gonna help
me with this.
I know Sofia is pregnant,
and I'm not going to allow it.
I need to protect my legacy.
[Olivia] Okay, I can try.
[recording tape stops]
[gentle dancing music]
[indistinct chattering]
[camera shutter clicking]
[gentle dancing music continues]
-[music fades]
-[background applause]
Hmm.
[soft music]
♪ At first I was afraid,
I was petrified ♪
♪ Kept thinking, I can never
live without you by my side ♪
♪ And I spent so many nights
thinking how you did me wrong. ♪
♪ And I grew strong, and now I
know how to get along... ♪
[door opens]
[woman] Sofia!
Hello, I'm here.
[crowd cheering]
Happy birthday to me.
-[background singing]
-[indistinct chattering]
You're looking so, so
beautiful tonight.
You look so beautiful,
glad to see you.
[background singing]
[Patrick] Sofia, happy birthday!
You look gorgeous, darling.
I have so much to tell you.
Don't tell me, please.
I love you.
[background singing continues]
[instrumental music]
I'm so happy to see you.
It's been a long time.
[inaudible]
[applause and cheering]
[instrumental music plays]
[indistinct chattering]
[applause and cheering]
[Olivia] Oh, happy birthday,
Sofia.
You look so wonderful.
I see we both came
for the gifts.
[instrumental music continues]
[applause]
Welcome to my island,
most of you anyway.
I'll be brief, unlike Comrade
Fidel, who couldn't come today.
He's too busy loading sugar
on my ships.
[crowd laughing]
Yes, we're here to
have a good time.
It's been years
since I've had a party here.
You know why.
I miss him, we all do.
He'd be there back there,
dying of embarrassment.
My son.
My boy.
Fuck, I never thought I'd still
be alive in my 60s.
[crowd laughing]
Since that caravan in Anatolia
where I was born in a tent
and almost died as a child and
those weeks in the desert,
eh Patrick?
Friends, underneath our suits
and our elegant dresses,
we are all naked.
[laughing and applause]
Sofia, my dear,
I'm here to give you the world.
You, and only you
will be living proof
of my existence.
We're all going to
remember you, Papa.
Darling, it's your birthday,
and I brought
you something very special.
You'll never forget this day.
None of us will.
[upbeat music playing]
[Marcos] Baby...
[crowd mesmerized]
[Sofia] Oh my God!
Happy birthday, Sofia
It's all yours.
[speaking foreign language]
-You like it?
-Oh my God!
Do I get to keep them both?
That unicorn isn't the only
animal with us here tonight.
[upbeat music continues]
♪ It's a hard world
to get it break in ♪
♪ All the good things
have been taken ♪
♪ But girl there are ways to
make certain things pay ♪
♪ Though I'm dressed
in these rags ♪
♪ I'll wear sable someday ♪
Please welcome
our English friend!
[upbeat music continues]
Where's Sofia?
Hello dear.
Happy birthday, Sofia,
this one is for you.
♪ It ain't no use,
holding me down ♪
♪ Sticking around ♪
-♪ So baby ♪
-[crowd] ♪ Baby ♪
-♪ Remember ♪
-[crowd] ♪ Remember ♪
♪ It's my life
and I'll do what I want ♪
♪ It's my mind
and I'll think what I want ♪
♪ It's my life
and I'll do what I want ♪
♪ It's my mind
and I'll think what I want ♪
♪ Show me I'm wrong ♪
♪ Hurt me sometime ♪
♪ But someday,
I'll treat you real fine ♪
-[crowd cheering]
-[music ends]
[woman] Wooh, I love you!
[woman] Wooh, I love you Eric!
[Sofia retching]
-[Olivia] Sofia.
-[knocking]
-[Sofia] One minute.
-[door opens]
[Olivia] Sofia,
it's me, Olivia.
Get out, get out.
-[door opens]
-How are you feeling, baby?
Shh.
[women entering bathroom,
chattering indistinctly]
- [Sofia] Just don't.
- [woman 1] I hooked up
with two of them.
It was nothing special at all.
I usually don't even
like Spanish men.
I really prefer Italian,
but this one, Carlos. [gasping]
[woman 2] Did you see his abs?
[woman 1] I mean, oh my God.
[laughing]
[woman 2] Did you see Olivia?
-She looks like shit.
-[toilet flushes]
She's only here to squeeze
whatever she can get
out of Marcos.
But time is up, baby!
[laughing]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[radio static]
[Sofia] Don't listen to them.
[Olivia] Thank you, Sofia.
Let's go and change.
Okay?
[Sofia] Mm-hmm.
[door opens]
[Olivia] I've been thinking
Carlos, he's an impressive kid.
Your father is thrilled
with him.
But this time,
the guy is actually worth it.
Really worth it.
And besides, the two of you
already know each other well.
Don't you think so?
[upbeat music]
♪ Ah, ah, ah ♪
[indistinct singing]
Oh darling.
Your father.
Oh, baby.
Will you help me?
[background music]
[applause]
Happy birthday to me too!
All right, I need two things.
I need a drink, and I need to
find out who these belong to.
Thank you!
[emcee] And now ladies
and gentlemen,
a short break
from the band.
The buffet is open.
[soft background music]
La gout is killing me.
My doctor told me that surgery
is not possible for this?
There is no surgery option for
gout, that's true.
The only thing
you can do is avoid
seafood, red meat and alcohol.
Come on, doctor, we are at the
time we have left.
[speaking foreign language]
[upbeat music plays]
[Carlos] I knew where we
were the whole time.
You overreacted, all of you.
It was my farm after all.
Yes, but it was my daughter.
I thought about shooting you.
You were what, 15, 16?
Yeah, something like that, yeah.
I've never seen my
daughter as radiant and as happy
as she was that summer.
Since she left for college,
I somehow lost her.
When I look at her,
I know, I want to believe she's
still there, hiding
inside herself, away from all
those assholes around her.
I believe God makes children
selfish, so parents can learn
how to live without them.
If they stayed as adorable as
when they were small, it would
be impossible to let them go.
But you are different, Carlos.
But I'm not like the
rest of my family.
Specifically, not like my
grandfather, Mr. Timoleon.
I'm not like him,
and I like your daughter.
Very much, you know that?
Yes.
I carry that summer inside me,
too.
But sir, let me say, I'm not
just a gift you can
give away with a pretty bow on.
I'm very fond of you, my boy.
You have all my respect, and I
have never put a bow on you yet.
[Carlos laughing]
Continue learning Greek,
just in case.
[upbeat music continues
in background]
[indistinct singing
Whatever happens here tomorrow,
we'll always take care of
that kid.
He's a magnificent young man.
Of course, sir.
She's waiting
for you at the office.
Very good.
[Marcos] Are you backing down?
I thought you were more
practical than that, Olivia.
Marcos, I don't want to go
through with this.
I'm so sorry, but I love you
both too much to do it.
[Marcos] Precisely.
Love is what it's all about.
To do good for love.
I told you, you can have
whatever you ask.
-[Olivia sighs]
-And then go on with your life.
You kill me with
your generosity.
[Marcos] Women like
you can't stand moderation.
They need constant excess.
Can you forget about me
for a second?
Marcos, we are talking
about your daughter.
You have no one else left apart
from her.
Now you're telling me how
to think?
I swore to myself that I would
never abandon my kids.
What are you talking about?
I need to take Sofia away from
her empty dreams,
keep her away from those people,
and from the fucking drugs.
I know, I'm certain that her
future and the future
of my legacy are the last thing
she wants right now.
If she even knows what she
wants, all the whining,
all the nonsense, come on,
honey, you know it as well.
Her future is decided with
or without your help.
My father abandoned me, I will
not do the same to my daughter.
Oh, okay, forget about me
signing anything.
If you want to keep living like
a queen at my expense,
you're going to have to earn it.
Marcos, you don't
understand anything.
I don't care about your money,
that's not why I'm here.
You know that, not everything in
life is fucking business.
I hate your money.
[sighing]
Baby...
I don't wanna hurt you.
Let me save you from yourself.
Hmm?
[belt unbuckling]
We still have time.
Don't you see?
It's not over yet.
[Olivia breathing heavily]
Get out of here.
[low heartbeat noise]
You insist on pushing me away.
[both breathing heavily]
I won't say it again.
[Olivia chuckles]
I will never leave you.
[door opens]
Sir, the band is ready.
[suspenseful music]
[suspenseful music continues]
[drumbeats]
[instrumental music]
[somber music]
[high-pitched music]
[instrumental music]
[applause and cheering]
[camera shutter clicking]
[instrumental music continues]
[indistinct chattering]
[eerie music]
[camera shutter clicks]
[indistinct screaming voices]
-[commotion]
-[guests shouting]
[Kostas shouting]
[man] Step back, step back,
step, sorry.
- What the hell is going on?
- [Kostas shouting]
[Kostas speaking
foreign language]
Sir...
Apologies, my friends.
These things happen.
Poor fool.
[cracking]
A few years ago,
we shot at paparazzi.
That's right, we shot at them.
We didn't shoot at them,
we shot at their balloon.
They were Japanese.
Paparazzi flying
over the island.
Remember, Kostas?
We had to fish them out
of the sea.
[crowd laughing]
A hot air balloon.
[chuckles]
It seems, it's good business to
sell naked pictures of myself.
Sofia, what are you doing?
Stop it.
[Marcos] Dema, bring the cake.
Olivia, she's on our side.
[all guests]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Sofia ♪
[man] Woo.
Thank you.
Make a wish.
[blowing]
[instrumental music]
[fireworks boom]
-[fireworks continue booming]
-[instrumental music continues]
[gun fires]
[upbeat music]
[Forster] So, you fought
in the war, Kostas?
-Yes.
-Against the Italians?
No.
Well, great then,
against the Nazis.
No.
[upbeat music continues
in background]
Come on Mr. Forster,
he's waiting for you.
[Forster] In a place like this
they finished with Rasputin.
It's not about the money,
you know.
Okay, Forster, okay.
It's always about money.
Christmas has come early
for you this year, my friend.
It's all there in writing, it's
clear, and you can have it all.
We'll publish it unedited?
Never ask for anything,
Forster, especially from those
more powerful than you.
This frees you of
any legal liability.
You can say, I'm the cousin of
Hitler, or I was born a woman.
You only need
to put in a number.
Ah, allow me.
But that baby will
never be born.
You won't be my son-in-law,
and you'll never see her again.
You know, Marcos, sometimes
there are things
in life that can't be bought.
I'm giving you a better start
than you could ever dream of.
You can even write
about all that's happening
here right now in your fucking
book if you like.
Pick it up or you're not
getting off this island.
I could bury you along with all
those other fools.
Or you can fuck my daughter
a few more times
and then fly away
for you to write about
whatever the fuck you want.
Your future is lying there.
Pick it up.
[chuckles]
[Marcos] You have a number,
make sure you put it on
the dotted line.
[footsteps receding]
-[insects chirring]
-[indistinct chattering]
Mr. Forster,
everything all right?
[background chattering]
[somber music]
[indistinct chattering with
somber background music]
[somber music continues]
[all laughing]
[instrumental music]
[somber music continues]
[Marisa] Sofia?
Hey, do we have enough photos?
[Marisa] Yeah, yeah,
don't worry.
It's important that we have
one with him.
[Marisa] Of course.
Come on.
[guests chattering]
[dramatic music]
[woman moaning]
[Marcos] I see right through
the expensive suits and
fancy dresses
at this party, and when I look
at you, I see nothing but
another parasite.
[dramatic music continues]
Stay away from my family.
Take your dollars and stuff them
in your filthy pockets and
pray, just pray, that I never
catch you snooping around again.
I know how this feels, maybe
better than you do.
I've been missing him my whole
life, you know that.
I know what he's like.
But the honest truth is
that I love him.
[Olivia sighing]
Marcos makes everything
else disappear.
Cold.
Pain.
Loneliness.
Everything.
Nothing could get to me
while I was there.
Wrapped in his warmth.
And you know, I think we could
have a few good years left.
You are the most dignified
woman I've ever met.
-[upbeat music]
-[indistinct chattering]
But-but now she's yours so you
can call her whatever you want.
I'm very fond of her, I had to
break the amniotic sac myself
as she was coming out because
her mother was really struggling
with the during labor.
Yeah, Papa say you're quite
the veterinarian.
Yes, I remember that you used
to love our horses.
I know, I used to love going
to the stables with you.
[laughing]
[upbeat music continues
in background]
[guests chattering indistinctly]
I fought in the
Battle of Athens,
I saw the Swastika waving
on the Acropolis.
How far away did you see the
Swastika from?
[Kostas laughing]
That's right, distance is a
very important thing, my friend.
Now you have to decide your own
distance from this place.
It's a world
you won't belong to.
Huh?
Timoleon, you and myself,
we come from totally
different places.
You are a writer,
and he respects you more
than you think.
His suffer can change your life.
Do you really want to become
Timoleon's hated son-in-law,
huh?
Do you really want to get on
that boat?
[Forster] Hmm.
Thank you.
Get out of here while you can.
[background music playing]
[lighter clicks]
Uh, Sofia, you know that our
parents want us to...
You know my father told me that
he was talking to your father--
Yeah, for fuck's sake, it's
not the Middle Ages.
I mean...
But I think we can be
really close friends.
[background music playing]
[suspenseful music]
[sighing]
-[background music continues]
-[guests chattering]
[inaudible]
Now?
I have to admit,
this is my place.
[upbeat music]
[cheering]
[upbeat music continues]
[water splashing]
[woman] Take it off, girl!
[cheering]
[speaking foreign language]
[crowd cheering]
[water splashing]
[upbeat music continues]
[speaking foreign language]
So impressive.
I also have a present for you.
Forgive me, Sofia.
After that day, I haven't really
known how to deal with you.
I didn't even know how
to talk to you.
[Sofia] I miss him, too, Dad.
When Daniel died,
you started to clean
his room like a crazy person.
Remember you put away his stuff
and all his clothes into
that chest.
And Daniel Demetrius was rubbing
the walls with bleach?
And you bolted up his door?
I tried to mold him, to change
him, tried to make
him in my own image, impossible.
You always needed that boy more
than he needed you, Papa.
What about me?
You never needed me.
You sent me away.
I have wonderful news.
Papa.
Do you already know?
That fucking bitch.
I don't need Olivia to tell me
what's going on in my own house
I've known about it all along.
You're not bringing
that child into this world.
End of story.
[Marcos] I know who's it is.
Yeah, because you have been
spying on me.
Just like you did with Mama,
right?
Putting your little
bugs everywhere,
making her believe
that life wasn't worth living.
Go, go to hell!
Sofia, our family is not like
any other family.
I will not leave a mess
behind after I die.
You're not having that baby.
And that guy, I opened my life
to him and he does this,
he's a fucking bastard.
And that shit you put in your
body, I know what it is.
What kind of baby would that be?
Have you thought about that?
I'm not a junkie.
It's the same shit you said
to Mama.
You're going to stay here with
me, everything will be fine.
It's for your own good.
[Sofia] I don't need
your permission.
I'm going to announce it to the
press tomorrow morning.
I have it all planned out.
With Ian, yeah?
Ian Forster.
A new Timoleon heir is coming
into the world.
You just think I'm stupid.
[Sofia scoffs]
Yeah, I sold the exclusives.
It's done.
And did you really think
that the musician
was the only photographer I
brought to the party?
I don't need your permission.
Everyone needs my permission.
All that shit
from your past is over.
Your Englishman and I are going
to come to an agreement today.
No one is going
to announce anything to anyone.
Everything's going to be fine,
and you're going to be happy,
no matter how
much you insist otherwise.
And that Forster guy,
he's mine.
I know you'd rather it'd be me
than Daniel.
That boat trip,
right after Mom died.
Do you remember?
Me and Danny,
we thought that we were running
away because you killed her.
Oh, I'm fed up with you women,
all my life surrounded by
crazy women, bitter women, with
insane thoughts in their head.
I never regret being unfaithful
to your mother.
Not once, not once, not at all.
Do you remember the seagulls?
[lighter clicks]
You were up at the deck shooting
at them with your rifle.
And you were drunk and naked.
[tense music]
Danny didn't dare to go up, but
I did and I saw the dead birds
floating around the boat.
And you looked at me
and you had a hard on.
That never happened.
Papa, you had a hard on.
Never, you're sick.
Oh my God, you can't be as
crazy as your mother.
I don't deserve it!
I'm so tired.
Everything's gonna be all
right, sweetheart.
[door opens, closes]
-[upbeat music]
-[guests chattering, laughing]
[Marisa speaking
foreign language]
[man speaking foreign language]
[both speaking foreign language]
[both moaning]
[background upbeat music]
[indistinct conversations]
[somber music]
Button up, my friend.
Come.
[somber music continues]
[knocking]
[Marcos] Come in.
[knocking again]
[Marcos] Come in!
[upbeat music in background]
[shower water running]
[dramatic music, singing in
foreign language]
[singing in foreign
language continues]
[singer] What are you thinking?
[singing in foreign
language continues]
[upbeat music]
[singing in foreign
language continues]
[Marcos mutters]
-We're the same age.
-Yes, I know.
Come on, my friend.
Go get some rest,
there's work to do tomorrow,
and I want this clean
and spotless by afternoon.
Yes, sir.
[singer] What are you thinking?
[camera shutter clicking]
[singing in foreign
language continues]
[upbeat music continues]
[singing in foreign
language continues]
[birds squawking]
[tape recorder plays]
[Sofia] My time has come.
And you know what?
It's gonna be a girl.
I feel it.
[tape recorder stops]
[silence]
[flies buzzing]
[Kostas] Sir?
Is that them?
[Kostas] Yes, we're ready.
Go get her.
[ship horn blows]
[indistinct chatter]
[insects chirping]
[door opens]
[speaking foreign language]
[both speaking foreign language]
That's everything then.
Everything that's needed, right?
Yes.
You know what'll happen if you
speak about any of this.
[door opens]
-[door closes]
-[Kostas] Sir.
We can't find Sofia.
Lock the island down.
[horn blows]
Sofia!
-Sofia!
-There it is.
-Sofia, Sofia.
[woman] Push, push.
[somber music]
Sofia!
[man speaking foreign language]
-[man] Sofia!
-[woman laughing]
[man] Okay, this is not funny,
guys.
[woman] Sofia!
Sofia!
[somber music continues]
[man] Sofia!
[man 2] Sofia, where
the fuck is she?
[suspenseful music]
[shrieking suspenseful music]
[Marcos shouting in
foreign language]
[Patrick] Don't just stand
there, get me some activated
charcoal for a nasal gas tube.
One gram per kilo,
let's go with 50 for now.
Maybe we'll do it after.
[Patrick] Have you
ever done that?
[Kostas] Not, for years.
[metal clanging]
[Patrick] Okay, first
things first.
A stomach pump, quickly!
[rustling]
[indistinct conversations]
[speaking foreign language]
[door closes]
[wind blowing]
[door opens]
What is this place, Marcos?
What have you done?
Oh, my God.
It's gonna be all right.
Everything is gonna
be all right.
Oh, my baby.
[water sloshing]
[indistinct music playing]
[camera shutter clicks]
[indistinct background music]
[man speaking foreign language]
[background music continues]
[ship horn blows]
She's stable now.
Still unconscious,
but it's all right now.
Sofia's pregnant, I want you
to take the baby away.
You have to do it now.
It's the best moment.
Now's the time.
When she recovers,
we'll tell her she lost it.
End of story.
You've really gone mad.
No, you don't understand,
I'm doing it for her.
If you don't do it,
the other guy will.
In fact, in 15 minutes,
he has orders to start.
I'd rather that you do it.
That's why I'm here after all
these years.
And just to make sure you also
call this village quack over.
I don't know you, Marcos,
or maybe I do.
I just don't like you anymore.
Would you stop being a prissy
fucking faggot for once
in your life?
Poor Marcos.
Sofia is not pregnant.
[Patrick] You raised a real
Timoleon, I'm afraid.
She's just like you.
A sweet-talking manipulator.
Jesus, what a mess.
This is the last time
we see each other.
Good.
Fuck you, Marcos.
I just hope you can forgive
yourself one day.
[door opens]
Patrick?
[door closes]
[Marcos] Now do as I told you,
I need to be sure.
[bag unzips]
[background rustling]
[eerie music]
[birds cawing]
[eerie music continues]
Ouch.
Papa?
Have you done something to me?
What have you done to me?
Sweetie, I don't think it's
okay for you to get up.
[Sofia groaning]
Seven weeks ago, I found
out I was pregnant.
It was a beautiful thing.
It really was a beautiful thing.
Hmm, but then I lost it.
I lost a baby.
I didn't tell Ian
because I hoped that I would
get pregnant again
before he found out.
I loved him.
[Sofia breathing heavily]
[somber music]
[Marcos] ♪ Baby,
can y'all understand me now? ♪
♪ Sometimes I get a little mad ♪
♪ Don't you know? ♪
♪ No one alive can
always be an angel ♪
♪ When things go wrong,
I seem to go bad ♪
♪ I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Hold on, please don't let me
be misunderstood ♪
[somber music continues]
♪ Baby, sometimes
I'm so carefree ♪
♪ With a joy
it's hard to hide it ♪
♪ And other times it seems
that all I ever have is worry ♪
♪ And then you're bound
to see my other side ♪
♪ I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Oh Lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood ♪
[somber music continues]
♪ I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good ♪
♪ Oh Lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood ♪
[song fading]
[water lapping]
[birds squawking]
[water lapping continues]
-[birds squawking]
-[water lapping continues]